bluetie.com 2016-06-09

# Privacy Policy »

### 1\. General

BlueTie respects the privacy of every individual who visits [www.bluetie.com ](http://www.bluetie.com/front)(the “Web Site” or “Site”). This Privacy Policy outlines the information we will collect and how we will use and share that information. This Policy will also tell you what to do if you do not want your personal information collected or shared. If you have any questions about our policy, you may contact us by email.

### 2\. Your Acceptance of These Terms

By using the Web Site, you signify your assent to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Policy, please do not use the Site. Your continued use of the Web Site following the posting of changes to its terms means you accept those changes.

### 3\. Personally-Identifiable Information

There are cases where we may ask you for personally-identifiable information such as your name, mailing address, email address and telephone number. We request personally-identifiable information when you register as a member of the Web Site, for online transactions, feedback forms, surveys and for other services that require registration or subscription. We will not collect any personally-identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. Please note that although certain registrations within BlueTie require certain user information, registration itself is entirely optional. We will also collect other users’ comments about you in our feedback area.

When you provide us with personally-identifiable information, BlueTie may:

  * store and process that information to better understand your needs, customize your experience, and to improve our products and services;
  * use that information to contact you periodically via email and postal mail for informational purposes (i.e. site updates, system outages, etc.);
  * disclose that information to third parties who need such information to provide products and services that you have requested;
  * disclose that information to 

## I. Service Availability

**a.  ** **Uptime.  **BlueTie shall provide 100.00% Service Availability, measured on a per calendar-month basis. Service Availability is defined as the ability of a subscriber to (a) send and receive messages via their mailbox using the Services and (b) access, view and create calendar events, tasks, and contacts, so long as subscriber is accessing Services in a manner consistent with approved and supported web browser, mail clients and mobile devices, and so long as provided account is active, in good standing and Services described herein are enabled. Unavailability caused by issues beyond BlueTie’s reasonable control, including, but not limited to, denial of service or similar attacks, DNS resolution failure, Domain Name expiration, Internet availability, mail bombs, or other Force Majeure event will be excluded from Service Availability calculations. Unavailability of Services due to Maintenance as described in Section II will be excluded from Service Availability calculations.

**b.  ** **Service Availability Monitoring and Reporting.**

i. BlueTie monitors its infrastructure and the Services but does not monitor individual mailboxes, desktop clients, mobile devices or otherwise availability. Service Availability is monitored internally and verified using 3rd party monitoring utilities. Monitoring checks are run at predefined intervals with failure thresholds defined with respect to the service being provided. If three or more consecutive tests should fail, the lack of Service Availability will be recorded as the number of minutes between the first and last failed tests. Any unavailability less than ten (10) minutes in duration will not be recorded.

ii.  BlueTie does not guarantee the delivery time of incoming and outgoing email, and as such does not include this in its calculations of Service Availability. If a delay in mail delivery is due to a complete Service, server or network outage, Service Availability is calculated as related to those services only. BlueTie will use commercially reasonable efforts to provide reasonable delivery times for incoming and outgoing mail delivery.

## II. Maintenance

**a.  ** **Scheduled Maintenance.  **BlueTie periodically performs maintenance on its infrastructure to ensure optimal performance and reliability. Scheduled Maintenance may occur between 1AM and 5AM Eastern Time. Service unavailability due to Scheduled Maintenance shall be excluded from Uptime calculations. BlueTie will use commercially reasonable efforts to provide notification of Scheduled Maintenance seven (7) days in advance.

**b.  ** **Emergency Maintenance.  **In certain circumstances, it may be deemed necessary to perform immediate maintenance on the system to ensure continued reliability which may or may not impact user access to Services. Service unavailability due to Emergency Maintenance shall be excluded from Uptime calculations.

**c.  ** **3 rd Party Provider Maintenance. **BlueTie contracts several 3rd party service providers in relation to the delivery of Services to users. BlueTie will make commercially reasonable efforts to provide notification of 3rd Party Provider Maintenance which may impact the availability of Services to users within one (1) day of receipt of this maintenance. Service unavailability due to 3rd Party Provider Maintenance shall be excluded from Uptime calculations.

## III. Service Availability Limitations

**a.  ** **Storage Capacity.  **Subscriber accounts are assigned a storage capacity limitation based on Service plan type. Upon reaching the storage capacity limit, access to send and receive messages will be revoked until such time as the account storage capacity is increased, or data is deleted to recover storage. Reaching the defined storage capacity limitation may lead to Service Unavailability and the loss of data, unrecoverable to the user. BlueTie is not liable for Service Unavailability or data loss as a result of exceeding the Subscriber defined storage limit.

**b.  ** **Anti-Virus Message Filtration.  **BlueTie utilizes 3rd party Anti-Virus filtering technology to scan messages entering the mail delivery infrastructure. Messages and/or attachments that cannot be filtered, contain viruses, phishing code, spoofed domains and headers, malware, Trojans or other threats may be permanently deleted and unrecoverable. ** ** BlueTie is not liable for lost or deleted messages or attachments filtered by Anti-Virus systems, and makes no warrantee to the accuracy of message filtering.

**c.  ** **Anti-SPAM Message Filtration.  **BlueTie utilizes a combination of proprietary and 3rd party Anti-SPAM message filtration technology to scan messages entering and exiting the mail delivery infrastructure for SPAM sources, content and non-compliant protocol usage, or other mechanisms designed to circumvent SPAM filtration. Messages may be blocked from entering the mail delivery infrastructure and may not be recoverable. BlueTie is not liable for lost, non-delivered, delayed or misclassified email messages filtered by the Anti-SPAM systems, and makes no warrantee to the accuracy of message filtering.

## IV. Credits for Non-Compliance

**a.  ** **Service Availability.  **If Service Availability is below 99.99%, BlueTie will issue a credit to the affected subscriber, reseller, or partner according to the following schedule:

SERVICE AVAILABILITY | CREDIT APPLIED  
---|---  
**99.8% to 99.99%** | **1% of monthly fee credited**  
**99.5% to 99.79%** | **2% of monthly fee credited**  
**98.3% to 99.49%** | **8% of monthly fee credited**  
**90.0% to 98.29%** | **20% of monthly fee credited**  
**89.9% and below** | **2.5% of monthly fee credited per 1% of downtime up to the maximum service credit**  
  
BlueTie calculates the credit for Service Availability based on the Credit Applied multiplied by the monthly fee for the number of Subscribers impacted. For example, for a Service Availability credit where two mailboxes are affected out of 10, Service Availability credit will be the total monthly fees multiplied by the Credit Applied and then multiplied by the percentage of users affected.

## V. Application for Service Availability Credit

To receive a credit, your account must (a) not have any past due balance at the time of the outage, and (b) an email must be sent to BlueTie’s Billing Department ([billing@bluetie.com](mailto:billing@bluetie.com)) within seven (7) days of the incident. The communication must include (i) the dates and times of each incident that you claim to have experienced including the relevant data center (if applicable) (ii) the relevant services for which a claim is being requested and (iii) supporting documentation to corroborate your claim.

## VI. Limitation of Service Availability Credits; Sole Remedy

Notwithstanding anything set forth in the Agreement, the credit described in Section IV A will be the sole remedy in connection with any Service unavailability, outages or breach of this Service Level Agreement by BlueTie. The limitation of service Availability Credits may not exceed 50% of the billed services monthly fees for the account during the month for which the credit is to be issued.

third parties when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) BlueTie’s rights or property, other members or users of the Web Site, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities; and

  * disclose that information to third parties when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

Except as stated in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise stated at the time personally-identifiable information is gathered, we will not provide personally-identifiable information to third parties.

### 4\. Non-Personally-Identifiable Information

BlueTie may also collect information about you that is not personally-identifiable. This type of information includes your age, gender, zip code, area code, interests and preferences. We will not collect any such information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. We may share this information in the aggregate with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. For example, we may inform a sponsor that the membership of the Web Site is x percent females and y percent males. These data are used to customize our Site’s content and advertising. We will also use that and other data and information to make visits to the Site easier, quicker, and better for you and our other members and users. We also may track certain information about your visit to the Web Site, including (without limitation) pages viewed, clickstreams, and searches. Such information is gathered in the aggregate and is not identified by any specific users.

### 5\. Other Special Circumstances

Contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions on the Site will have separate privacy practices with regard to the information collected in connection with entering or participating in any such event. You will have a choice of whether or not you would like to allow certain information shared with third parties who may have a product or service of interest to you. You will also have the choice of whether a company that is co-sponsoring a promotion or contest may contact or send information to you.

### 6\. Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

### 7\. Information Collected Automatically

BlueTie may also automatically collect non-personally-identifiable information about your use of the Web Site, such as the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com, if you are connecting from an America Online account), the date and time you access the Site, and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our Site. This information will not be linked to personally-identifiable information. We may use this information to analyze and enhance our Web Site and for security purposes, and we may aggregate this information and share the aggregated information with business partners, sponsors, and other third parties.

### 8\. Information Placed Automatically On Your Computer’s Hard Drive

Not all cookies are edible. A “cookie” is information stored on your computer when you view a website. Our cookies help us in many ways. For example, a cookie is used to remember your username (if desired). This means that the next time you log in to BlueTie, you will only have to enter your password. If you visit another website from our Site, you may also receive a cookie or similar file from that site. With most Internet browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. Remember, however, that blocking or deleting cookies may limit your ability to access some or all of the features and services of the Web Site.

### 9\. Uploaded Information

We will not disclose to third parties any information, data and other materials that you upload to any non-public areas of the service offered on the Web Site (e.g., your calendar, your file folders, etc.) except as directed by you or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

### 10\. Changing or Deleting Your Personal Information

BlueTie allows you to modify or delete your personal information or preferences, by clicking on the “Edit My Info” link in the top right corner of the navigation. You may also call BlueTie at 1-800-BLUE-TIE to request account cancellations or information changes.

### 11\. Children

The Web Site is not directed at individuals under thirteen years of age, and BlueTie does not intend to collect any personally-identifiable information from such individuals.

### 12\. Links to Other Websites

The Web Site allows links to various other web sites. We assume no responsibility for the information practices of sites you are able to access through the Web Site. Furthermore, a link to another does not imply an affiliation or an endorsement of that linked site.

### 13\. Security

Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information online — for example, via instant messaging or online meetings— that information can be collected and used by people you don’t know. While BlueTie strives to protect your information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online, and you do so at your own risk.

The importance of security for all personally-identifiable information associated with our users and members is of utmost concern to us. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personally-identifiable information, we can’t ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. However, once we receive your personally-identifiable information, we will take reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

In certain areas BlueTie uses SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions.

Your account on the Web Site is password protected so that only you can access it and view the member information relevant to the account. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. BlueTie will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or email. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. Remember to sign out of your account on the Web Site and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This will ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if your computer is accessible to others, if you share a computer with someone else, or if you use a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafè.

### 14\. Privacy Policy Changes

If we decide to materially change our privacy policy for BlueTie, we will prominently post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone.

### 15\. Whom to Contact

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact BlueTie at:

Privacy Policy  
BlueTie, Inc.  
2480 Browncroft Blvd, Suite 2b  
Rochester NY 14625  
Or, you may contact us by email.
